Where is Tatsuji Iinuma?
飯沼達次在哪裡？
I cannot tell you that.
我不能告訴你
You must be careful not to leak information about the patient.
千萬不要洩漏病患的資訊
By the way…
還有一件事
Your heart…
你的心臟…
still hasn't been entirely cured.
沒有完全治癒
The Caesar operation was a temporary emergency treatment.
凱撒手術只是做緊急處理而已
If you have a heart attack,
要是心臟病發作
you'll only have a couple of hours left.
你只剩下幾小時能活
I recommend a second surgery as soon as possible.
我建議你盡快進行第二次手術
But of course,
不過，能做到的
I'm the only one who can do it.
當然只有我了
So I will ask you once again.
所以我再問一次
Where is Tatsuji Iinuma now?
飯沼達次在哪裡？
Threatening your patients now, are you?
威脅病患嗎？
That's unbecoming of a doctor.
醫生這樣非常要不得
I saved your life.
我救了你的命
I'm free to use it as I please.
怎麼處置是我的自由
I cannot tell you.
我不能告訴你
I have no intention of undergoing surgery right now.
不管怎樣，我現在不打算做手術
The election is in three days.
三天後就是理事長的選舉
Will you last that long?
你能撐到那時候嗎？
Well,
好吧
since you are my attending physician
既然你是我的主治醫生
maybe I'll have you come with me.
你也一起去吧
The election will be held in Tokyo.
競選將在東京的學術會議上進行
If something were to happen to me there,
如果那段期間我出事
no one will ever know where Mr. Iinuma is.
飯沼的下落可就沒人知道了
It would be wise for you to keep an eye on me.
你最好還是盯著我吧
Are you giving up on your search?
你放棄了嗎？
For Tatsuji Iinuma?
不找飯沼達次了？
I have a fairly good idea of where to find him.
我大概知道他在哪裡了
In that case, I'll be leaving it to you.
那我就不再插手了
Goodbye.
再見
Even if that patient was a victim of medical malpractice?
如果這個患者與醫療過失有關呢？
Medical malpractice…
醫療過失…
is unforgivable.
是不可原諒的
I agree.
是啊
Well,
這樣的話
shall I fill you in then?
要不要聽我說呢？
An aortic dissection?
主動脈剝離嗎？
Dr. Tokai really did it this time.
渡海那傢伙這次真的疏忽了
Will Mr. Iinuma be okay like this?
飯沼先生這樣下去沒關係嗎？
The only person who can operate on that patient…
能為他做手術的人
is me.
只有我
Take care of things while I'm away, will you?
我不在的期間，請你多關照他
Understood.
我明白了
I'm currently laying the groundwork with the board members,
我們正在爭取理事的支持
but as of now, the votes appear to be evenly matched.
目前票數似乎平分秋色
It can't be!
怎麼會這樣！
Normally,
正常情況下
I was supposed to win by a landslide!
我應該能贏得壓倒性勝利的！
I've decided that the paper from Tojo
我認為東城大學的論文
will better benefit future patients.
未來更能嘉惠病患
Both Ikenaga and Takashina…
池永和高階
stabbing me in the back…
居然在最後一刻
at the final moment!
從背後捅我一刀！
As planned, this weekend Dr. Saeki will be attending
這週末，佐伯教授將按計畫
the Surgical Society board meeting in Tokyo.
出席在東京舉行的外科學會會議
Is that a good idea? We hear his condition is still critical.
這樣可以嗎？聽說他的狀況還很危急
Dr. Tokai has decided to go with him.
渡海答應和他一起去
While Dr. Saeki is gone, the one taking responsibility is…
另外，教授不在期間 外科的負責人…
Dr. Takashina.
高階醫生
He's asking you to do it.
由你代理
Me?
我嗎？
Dr. Saeki's orders.
是佐伯教授指定的你
So Dr. Takashina has finally earned the professor's trust?
高階醫生終於得到教授的信任了
Frustrating as it is, he deserves the credit.
雖然很不服氣，他是實至名歸
Let's all give our support to the professor.
我們一起支持教授吧
We're counting on you.
拜託你了
Understood.
是
Dr. Tokai.
渡海醫生
Just as you thought you were abandoned by Dr. Nishizaki,
還以為你被西崎大醫生拋棄了
you find yourself as Seigo Saeki's right-hand man.
現在卻成了佐伯清剛的得力助手
One man's trash
某人眼裡的廢物
is another man's treasure.
卻是另一個人眼裡的寶
What you told me before…
你之前說的話
would you please explain what you meant?
可以解釋一下嗎？
Seigo Saeki.
佐伯清剛
Don't believe him.
不要相信他
That man…
那傢伙
betrayed my father.
背叛了我爸爸
is a god of death.
根本就是死神
Pardon me.
打擾了
I've brought your meal…
幫您送餐來了
Dr. Tokai, it's about your business trip schedule…
渡海醫生，關於出差的行程…
I found it. There really is a pair of forceps.
找到了，真的有一把止血鉗
The patient's name is Tatsuji Iinuma.
患者叫飯沼達次
Physician's name, Ichiro Tokai.
負責醫生，渡海一郎
What happened?
怎麼了嗎？
He left them inside the patient.
是他把止血鉗留在病患體內
Clearly medical malpractice.
這明顯是醫療過失
After his incriminating mistake,
犯了這個失誤後
Dr. Tokai was expelled from Tojo.
渡海一郎遭到東城大學開除
TO: SEISHIRO TOKAI CONTENTS: RICE
（渡海征司郎收 內容物：白米）
Hanabusa.
花房護理師
Dr. Sera.
世良醫生
It's about the forceps. I think it was more than just malpractice--
關於止血鉗那件事 渡海醫生的過失…
Shouldn't we leave this alone?
那件事就別再提了吧
SENDER: HARUE TOKAI
（寄件人：渡海春江）
Mr. Iinuma! Where were you?
飯沼先生，您跑到哪去了？
Just to the shop downstairs.
只是去了樓下的小店
If you need something, you can just tell me.
需要什麼就告訴我
That's why I'm here.
我是負責照顧您的人
Having things taken care of for me is nice,
有人照顧真的很好
but it feels like I'm being held captive.
只是感覺好像被軟禁一樣
That's not true.
怎麼會呢？
You need to take it easy.
您必須好好靜養
Take it easy? So when is my surgery?
靜養？我什麼時候動手術？
At Sakura Hospital, they told me it was urgent.
櫻花醫院的人說我必須馬上做手術
Surgery?
手術嗎？
Mr. Iinuma!
飯沼先生
You must be careful not to leak information about the patient.
千萬不能洩露患者的資訊
-Mr. Iinuma's condition has worsened. -He needs hemostatic agent.
-飯沼先生的病情惡化了 -他需要止血劑
-Get the hemostatic agent. I'm on my way. -Right!
-準備止血劑，我馬上過去 -是
-Hey! -Oh, pardon me.
對不起
-What is it? -It's nothing.
-怎麼了？ -沒事
The executive suite there?
那邊的特別單人房？
There's no patient in there.
應該沒有住患者才對
I'll operate.
我去處理
Your wounds haven't healed yet.
你的傷口還沒癒合
-The patient comes first. -You're a patient too!
-病患優先 -你現在也是病患
You won't be able to attend the election.
你會不能參加理事長競選的
I'm looking for hemostatic agent.
我需要止血劑
It's not here. You'll need to get it from the storage room.
這裡沒有，得去儲藏室拿
Thanks.
好的
Was there someone using hemostatic agent?
有人需要止血劑嗎？
I haven't received any reports.
我沒收到通報
-Nurse! -Have you told anyone?
-護士長 -你有告訴任何人嗎？
I haven't said a word.
我什麼都沒說
I administered first aid.
我已經急救過
His condition has stabilized,
他的情況穩定了
but there may be intrathoracic bleeding.
但還是有可能會胸腔內出血
He'll need surgery right away.
他需要盡快動手術
Show me the patient's data.
請給我看看這位患者的病歷
I cannot do that.
沒辦法
This is a special patient. His information must remain private.
這位是特別患者，他的病歷不能公開
Private?
不能公開？
That is the professor's order.
這是教授的命令
Sorry to show up out of the blue.
不好意思突然來打擾您
-You're still young, so eat up. -Thank you.
-你還年輕，多吃點 -謝謝
Japanese bodies are made from rice, you know.
日本人的身體是白米做的
That's right.
是啊
Yes.
對
So, Dr. Tokai's father…
那個，渡海醫生的父親
-What kind of doctor was he? -What kind?
-是怎樣的醫生？ -怎樣的？
Just a normal doctor.
就是普通的醫生
Putting his heart and soul into the care of each patient,
全心全意照顧每位患者
spending days upon days away from home.
有時候好幾天都不回家
-I see… -Oh.
-了解 -是啊
Want to see his photo album?
想看他爸爸的相本嗎？
-It's in my son's room. -Sure.
-在我兒子的房裡 -好
-Go ahead. -Thank you, pardon me.
-請進 -謝謝，我進來了
All these surgical ties…
這麼多外科打結…
Amazing.
太驚人了
Wow.
天啊
This is simply amazing.
真的很不得了
My son…
我兒子…
He used to work at a city hospital.
以前在市立醫院工作
He did?
是嗎？
After his father died, all of a sudden
他爸爸突然過世後
he said he wanted to transfer to Tojo.
他說要去東城大學醫院
He started working hard.
他開始變成拼命三郎
He's lucky that Dr. Saeki took a liking to him.
他很幸運，受到佐伯醫生的賞識
He did all this to become a doctor at Tojo?
他這麼努力都是為了去東城當醫生？
SCHEDULED FOR RECONSTRUCTION
（預定施工地）
Seishiro.
征司郎
What kind of doctor do you want to be?
你想成為什麼樣的醫生？
A regular doctor is fine.
普通的醫生就行了
No matter the age, people stay the same.
不管時代怎麼變，人都不會變
A doctor is a doctor.
醫生就是醫生
Just be yourself. Become a regular doctor.
你做自己就好，當個普通的醫生
Cut it out.
別鬧了
I'll send him to hell.
我會送他下地獄
About the executive suite,
是特別單人房
Nurse Fujiwara appears to be watching the patient around the clock.
藤原護理長 好像24小時照顧那位患者
Even if you know Mr. Iinuma's whereabouts, it's hard to tell what will happen.
就算知道飯沼先生的藏身處 也沒法採取什麼行動
I'm not worried about that.
這我不擔心
I've already decided.
我已經決定了
I have one chance.
我只有一次機會
It all ends there.
然後一次做個了結
Tomorrow is finally election day.
明天就是理事長競選日了
Here's to Dr. Saeki's victory.
這杯敬佐伯教授成功當選
Cheers!
乾杯
-Dr. Sera. -Yes?
-世良 -是
Excuse me.
不好意思
-Pardon me. -Keep an eye on Dr. Tokai.
-不好意思 -盯著渡海醫生
Don't leave his side until we return to Tojo.
我們回東城大學之前緊緊跟著他
Don't let him leave your sight.
別讓他離開你的視線
These are my orders.
這是我的命令
Yes, sir.
是
-Thanks. -Pardon me.
-謝謝 -不客氣
It's a waste of time.
都是浪費時間罷了
The editor-in-chief of the Japan Surgical Journal, Mr. Ikenaga,
等一下《日本外科雜誌》的池永主編
will soon be here to greet you.
會過來打招呼
-I'll wait in my room. -Okay.
-我去房間等他 -好
-Professor! -Doctor!
-教授 -醫生！
Professor!
教授！
Pericardial fluid is leaking into his chest.
應該是心包膜液漏到胸腔去了
We can't perform a thoracentesis in a place like this.
不能在這裡做胸腔穿刺吧
-What should we do? -We'll do it here.
-該怎麼辦？ -就在這裡做
What? Here?
什麼？在這裡？
-Roll his shirt up. -Right.
-幫他翻身 -是
Towel.
毛巾
Bring more towels.
多拿幾條毛巾過來
-Get ready to carry him out. -Right.
-準備把他送出去 -是
-Get a stretcher. -Okay.
-把擔架搬過來 -好
I'll let you live a bit longer.
先讓你留住這條命
Your own hell is still waiting.
你的地獄還在前面等著
Professor Saeki.
佐伯教授
Mr. Ikenaga is worried about you.
池永主編很擔心您
We asked him to leave, but…
我們請他回去，但…
-It's fine. Let him come in. -Right.
-沒關係，讓他進來 -好
-Let him in. -Okay.
-讓他進來 -是
Where's Tokai?
渡海人呢？
Resting in his room with Sera.
跟世良在房裡休息
I see.
這樣啊
Dr. Saeki…
佐伯醫生
How are you feeling?
您身體怎麼樣？
I'm fine.
我沒事
I guess I'll stay here.
那我就睡這裡了
ELECTION DAY
（理事長選舉日當天）
It's time for the handover. I'll step out for a bit.
交接時間到了，我出去一下
-Will you be okay? -Yes.
-你自己可以吧？ -可以
-What's wrong? -I'm going for a walk.
-您怎麼了？ -去散個步
I want something to drink.
順便買飲料
You need to rest.
您必須休息
Can't I just go out?
我就不能出去一下嗎？
If you need something, I'll get it.
如果有什麼想買的，我去幫您買
Fine.
好吧
A drink, right? I'll be right back.
想買飲料嗎？我馬上去
You're fast.
這麼快
Who are you?
你是誰？
Oh, no.
糟了
Dr. Tokai, it's almost time to…
渡海醫生，差不多該…
So we finally meet.
總算見到你了
What do you mean by "forceps"?
你說的止血鉗是什麼東西？
A surgical tool.
那是手術器具
Please wait.
請你等一下再進去
That tool is inside your body.
那個器具在你身體裡
What? There's no way.
什麼？這怎麼可能
If we take an X-ray, you'll see.
拍個X光片就知道了
Let's go.
我們去拍吧
That's enough.
夠了
Get out. My physician is Dr. Saeki.
你快出去，我的主治醫生是佐伯醫生
I won't trust anyone else besides Dr. Saeki.
除了佐伯醫生，其他人我都不相信
He's the reason I've stayed healthy all these years.
這麼多年來 多虧他，我的身體才一直很健康
All these years?
這麼多年？
You had a heart operation here at Tojo some years ago, right?
幾年前你在這裡動過心臟手術吧？
The operating surgeon was Dr. Saeki.
當時執刀的是佐伯醫生
Am I wrong?
沒錯吧？
Why do you care?
那又怎麼樣？
So you admit it.
所以你承認了
-I'll be using that as your testimony. -My testimony?
-我希望你能出來作證 -作證？
To expose the crimes of Dr. Seigo Saeki.
為了揭發佐伯清剛的罪行
And what crime would that…
佐伯醫生到底有什麼罪…
PULSE
（脈搏）
-Mr. Iinuma! -Give him oxygen.
-飯沼先生 -給他氧氣
-Okay. -You, bring the X-ray machine.
-是 -把X光機搬來
Okay.
好
Mr. Iinuma, can you hear me?
飯沼先生，您沒事吧？
Hello, this is Fujiwara.
喂，我是藤原
I can't find Dr. Tokai. He must be on his way there.
渡海不見了，可能是去那裡了
I'll look now.
我馬上去看看
Did Dr. Tokai go back to Tojo?
渡海醫生回東城大學了嗎？
Call Dr. Kurosaki. I need to ask him for a favor.
去叫黑崎醫生過來，我有事拜託他
Okay.
是
Dr. Tokai.
渡海醫生
What are you doing?
你在幹什麼？
Inside this patient's chest is a pair of forceps.
這位病人的胸腔裡有一把止血鉗
Forceps?
止血鉗？
What are you talking about?
你胡說什麼？
The doctor has entrusted me with the hospital while he's out.
教授要我請託我管理外科
Don't do as you please.
拜託你別亂來
It's Nurse Fujiwara. I'll have to report this.
是藤原護理長打來的 我要向她報告這件事
-Yes? -Where are you, Dr. Takashina?
-喂？ -高階醫生，你在哪裡？
I would like you to check on the executive suite.
能不能請你去特別單人房看一下？
That's where I am right now.
我就在這裡
Did something happen?
發生什麼事了嗎？
Trust me.
相信我
What is it? Did something happen?
怎麼了，出什麼事了？
It's…
就是…
The patient wanted something to drink.
病患想喝飲料
May I give him some vegetable juice?
可以給他喝蔬菜汁嗎？
Yes, of course.
當然可以
Go ahead.
麻煩您了
You need to tell me exactly what happened.
可以解釋清楚是怎麼回事嗎？
I'll show you.
我讓你看吧
There's no way…
不可能啊
There's really a pair of forceps…
真的有一把止血鉗在裡面
My father was wrongfully accused of medical malpractice.
我爸爸被控醫療過失，但是被冤枉的
This was all the work of Dr. Saeki.
這都是佐伯幹的好事
You'll need to receive a testimony from the patient himself.
你會需要病患本身出面作證
The reason you've stayed at Tojo
你一直待在東城大學
and continued to follow Dr. Saeki's orders
並對佐伯教授言聽計從
was because of this?
都是因為這個嗎？
That's why I have to keep this patient alive.
所以才必須保住這位患者的命
I need to get my hands on the root of all this.
我必須取得這一切爭議的根源
The forceps.
那把止血鉗
However…
可是…
without Dr. Saeki's permission--
沒有佐伯教授的允許…
When it's necessary…
必要的時候
…the rules can be changed.
就改變規定吧
Today,
今天
I will end it all.
我會把這件事做個了結
Professor Nishizaki and Professor Saeki.
西崎教授和佐伯教授
Which of these men will take the position of chairman?
究竟哪一位會接下理事長職位？
It will be decided by the board members after the presentation
等聽完兩位教授發表的研究成果後
of their respective research topics.
再由各位理事做出決定
I'm greatly looking forward to the results.
我很期待聆聽研究成果
Professor. About your orders.
教授，您吩咐的那件事
It has been taken care of.
已經辦好了
-Miwa, bring the thoracotomy device. -Right.
-美和，拿肋骨撐開器來 -是
Prepare for intubation after finishing the A-line.
動脈導管放置好就準備插管
What going on?
怎麼會這樣？
What are you doing here? Get out.
你在幹什麼？出去
-I'll call the others. -Go ahead.
-我要叫人了 -請便
But if you do,
但如果叫人
everyone will find out about the forceps Dr. Saeki left in the patient.
佐伯醫生在病人體內 留下止血鉗的事就會曝光了
I won't let you get in the way.
我不會讓你礙事的
Preparations complete.
準備好了
Okay, Miwa. Time for you to leave.
那麼美和，你出去吧
What? Why?
為什麼？
We don't need you.
這裡不需要你
You're in the way.
礙事
You must understand.
你能理解吧
We're operating on Dr. Saeki's patient.
我們在未經教授允許下替病患動手術
You're an intelligent and skilled nurse.
你是聰明又有才能的護理師
Think about your future.
想想自己的前途吧
Get out, now!
快出去
-We'll take out the forceps. -Right.
-現在來取出止血鉗吧 -是
-Scalpel. -Here.
-手術刀 -這裡
We'll now move on to the research presentations.
那麼，接下來開始進行研究成果發表
First, we'll hear from Teika University's surgeon, Dr. Keisuke Nishizaki.
首先有請 帝華大學外科教授西崎啟介醫生
Thank you.
有勞你了
We'll start with the dissection around the adhesion area.
先從沾黏部分周邊開始剝離
-Electroscalpel. -Here.
-電動手術刀 -是
After receiving high praise for my research on the Caesar,
我對國產凱撒機器人的研究 獲得高度評價
I'm nearing my goal of making it widely available in Japan.
只差一步 我就能達成讓它普及到全國的目標
Without having to call upon the aid of foreign countries,
今後我們不必再依賴外國技術
I believe it is time for Japan to act independently
是時候讓日本獨立自主
and pour our strength and resources into advanced medical research.
傾注力量與資源 在先進醫療研究領域了
For the experts who pride themselves on their personal skill,
當然，對於那些 以個人技術自豪的專家們來說
this may be a slightly unpleasant reality.
這可能不是好事吧
Here. Dissection complete.
好了，剝離完成
-Metz, please. -Here.
-請給我手術剪 -好
This is taking a lot of time.
光是這個已經花很多時間
I see it.
看到了
I can see it.
看得到了
As for especially skilled surgeons,
但技術高超的外科醫生
just how many are there in Japan?
全日本一共有多少人呢？
And in that one doctor's lifetime,
而且，那些醫生一輩子
just how many patients can they save?
又能救多少病人？
We finally meet.
終於看到了
I can't believe it. There are forceps in his heart.
真是難以置信 他的心臟裡真的有止血鉗
Taking them out.
拔出來吧
-He's bleeding. Blood pressure dropping. -I can't locate the source.
-出血了，血壓下降 -看不到出血位置
-Get the Satinsky clamp. -We have no free hands.
-給我靜脈鉗 -沒人手了
-I'll go. -I'll stop the bleeding.
-我去 -我來止血
-Hurry. -Understood.
-快點 -是
Sorry, I'm late. I have the Satinsky clamp.
抱歉，我來晚了，這是靜脈鉗
Here you are.
麻煩了
This is my patient. He was entrusted to my care.
這是我的病患，由我負責照顧
Nekota, support Dr. Tokai.
貓田護理師，您協助渡海醫生
I'll get whatever you need.
我來準備您需要的東西
He's losing more blood.
出血量又增加了
-Stitching, 3-0 please. -Right.
-開始縫合，3-0縫線 -是
-Two felt pieces.
-兩片組織修補片
To save even more lives,
為了拯救更多患者
we need to popularize the latest medical technology
我們應該讓最新的醫療技術普及化
and no longer rely on the skills of a medical surgeon alone.
不再只是依靠 個別外科醫生的高超技術
Realizing accessible medical care for all
實現人人都能得到醫療照護的目標
is a necessity above all else.
是最重要的
We will now take a short 15-minute intermission.
接下來休息15分鐘
Dr. Saeki's presentation is next.
下一個換佐伯教授上台
What should we do?
該怎麼辦？
-Using the Metz next. -Okay.
-接著給我手術剪 -是
-Metz. -Here.
-手術剪
The bleeding has stopped for now.
出血暫時止住了
I have to get them out.
我一定要拿出來
I'll get the forceps out.
我一定要取出止血鉗
The adhesion is terrible.
沾黏得很嚴重
That's because it's vintage.
因為放太久了
I hope the patient can hold out.
希望病患能撐住
If we can get the forceps out, he'll be saved.
如果能取出止血鉗，他就能活命
After that, I'll have him confess everything he knows.
之後，我會要他坦承一切
It's almost time.
時候到了
This is where it will all end.
這樣一切就都結束了
No. We have to stop them.
不行，一定要阻止他們
-I won't let you go. -Get out of my way.
-我不會讓你進去 -讓開
Stop!
住手
Don't take them out.
不要取出來
Dr. Saeki? Dr. Sera.
佐伯醫生？世良醫生
Dr. Saeki…
佐伯醫生
How did he get here…
他怎麼來的…
I took a medical helicopter.
我搭乘醫療直升機
Dr. Kurosaki prepared it for me.
黑崎醫生幫我安排的
Well…
那個…
in place of Dr. Saeki…
我是黑崎醫生
I, Kurosaki,
我要代替佐伯教授
will be presenting his research.
發表研究結果
-What happened to Dr. Saeki? -What could it be?
-佐伯教授怎麼了？ -怎麼回事？
At the renowned Tojo University…
在我們大名鼎鼎的東城大學…
So he bailed at the last second, did he?
在最後一刻跑了嗎？
You threw away the election to come here?
居然拋下理事長選舉跑回來？
Are you that afraid of your past?
你就這麼害怕過去的事曝光嗎？
I'm here to save the patient.
我是為了拯救患者的性命
Dr. Tokai. Don't touch those forceps.
渡海，不要碰止血鉗
All you want to save is your prestige.
你只是想要維護自己的名聲吧
-I'm telling you not to… -Shut up!
-我說不準取出… -閉嘴
I'm almost finished.
馬上就好了
We're almost done, Dad.
爸，馬上就要結束了
Watch me, Saeki!
等著瞧吧，佐伯
With this pair of forceps, I finally have undeniable proof
有了這把止血鉗，我就掌握了
of your crimes.
你犯罪的證據
Stop, Dr. Tokai!
渡海，住手
This is the end for you.
你玩完了
Apologize.
快道歉
Apologize to me first.
先跟我道歉
And then apologize to my father.
然後跟我爸道歉
My father lost everything to these forceps,
我父親因為這把止血鉗失去一切
and now, it's your turn!
現在輪到你了
Don't!
住手！
Goodbye,
再見
Dr. Seigo Saeki.
佐伯清剛
Dr. Tokai.
渡海醫生
-Blood pressure, 50! -3-0. 3-0.
-血壓50 -3-0縫線！
-Stop the blood! -Apply pressure. 3-0!
-快止血 -加壓，3-0縫線
-We need gauze. -Right.
-拿紗布來 -是
-As much as you can. -Okay.
有多少拿多少
-Saturation dropping. -Miwa, gauze!
-血氧飽和度下降 -美和，紗布！
-Dr. Tokai… -We have VF!
-渡海醫生… -出現心室纖維顫動
Damn.
可惡
No matter how much we suture, it won't stop.
無論怎麼縫血都止不住
Not even Dr. Tokai can stop it?
居然連渡海醫生都沒辦法止住
-3-0! -Here.
-3-0縫線 -是
You've opened up the gates of hell.
你打開了地獄之門
Dr. Saeki.
佐伯醫生
Move it.
讓開
Tokai.
渡海
I will deal with it.
我來處理
By forcing the forceps out, you've injured the aortic arch.
因為強行取出止血鉗 主動脈弓受損了
-I'll take over. -First, we stitch the aortic arch.
-我來接手 -首先縫合主動脈弓
-Run the heart-lung machine. -Right.
-開啟人工心肺機 -是
-Cool down to 25 degrees Celsius.
-降溫到25度
-Cooper. -Okay.
-庫博氏剪刀 -是
What do you plan on doing?
你打算怎麼做？
Dr. Tokai, listen.
渡海，聽著
If I couldn't fix it,
如果我無法補救
there's no way you'll be able to.
你也不可能做得到
Just listen to me.
總之你聽好
This wasn't forgotten because of negligence.
這個並不是疏忽才留在裡面
On that day, there was a large-scale bus accident.
那天附近發生了大客車事故
A number of patients were brought in.
很多患者被送來
At that time, I realized that one of our patients, Mr. Iinuma,
那時我發現住院的飯沼先生
had taken a turn for the worse, so I went to care for him.
病情突然惡化，所以我去幫他處理
But the operation rooms were full, leaving no extra staff to help.
但是手術室全滿，沒有多餘人手幫忙
Not knowing how to possibly stop the bleeding,
無論怎麼做，飯沼先生還是出血不止
I was left with no option
我已經無計可施
and left the forceps inside his body.
只好把止血鉗留在他體內
That was the only way.
那是唯一的辦法
Soon after,
不久之後
I was sent on a long-term medical assistance job in Africa.
我被派去非洲進行長期醫療支援
But the unexpected happened.
但是卻發生意想不到的事
Mr. Iinuma, who was supposed to have been discharged,
原本應該平安出院的飯沼先生
was brought in again in an emergency while I was away.
卻在我離開期間，送來醫院急診
The doctor put in charge was Dr. Ichiro.
負責他的醫生就是一郎醫生
When he looked inside Mr. Iinuma's chest,
他檢查飯沼先生的胸腔時
how surprised he must have been.
想必很吃驚吧
-Prepare for puncture immediately. -Right.
-馬上準備穿刺 -是
There's a call for you--
有電話找您…
I heard the news, but I had no phone line or time to spare.
我收到通知 但由於無法通電話也分身乏術
I sent a telegram to Dr. Ichiro.
就緊急發電報給一郎醫生
DO NOT TAKE MR. IINUMA'S FORCEPS
（不要取出飯沼先生的止血鉗 相信我）
Dr. Ichiro realized that those forceps were necessary for the procedure.
一郎醫生意識到那把止血鉗是必要的
Administer Revolade and close him up.
注射血小板增生劑然後縫合
Leaving the forceps inside the patient,
就讓止血鉗留在原處
Mr. Iinuma's procedure and operation were completed.
一郎醫生就這樣完成了手術
But after surgery, when your father was checking the X-rays,
但手術後，當你父親檢視X光片時
Dr. Kurosaki walked in on him and saw it.
黑崎醫生正好走進來看到了
It was declared medical malpractice,
醫院認定是醫療過失
and Dr. Ichiro received harsh criticism.
一郎醫生也飽受責難
You're a disgrace to Tojo University!
你是東城大學之恥！
In the end, Dr. Ichiro made no further objections,
最後一郎醫生沒有再多做反駁
accepted that it was his own mistake,
承認是自己的失誤
and left Tojo University.
離開了東城大學
The professor told me only after I returned to Japan.
等我回國後，教授才告訴我這件事
But it was too late.
但為時已晚
Dr. Ichiro was stricken with illness and he passed away.
一郎醫生已經因疾病纏身撒手人寰了
HE PASSED THE OTHER DAY
（他前天過世了）
After that,
之後
I received a letter from Dr. Ichiro.
我收到一郎醫生的信
To my sworn friend, Seigo Saeki.
致我的盟友佐伯清剛
You don't need to say anything.
什麼都不用說
A doctor needs only to think of their patients.
醫生只要考慮患者
Save lives.
救人性命就好
Save Mr. Iinuma.
要治好飯沼先生
I entrust everything to you.
我把一切都交付給你了
Knowing he didn't have much time left,
一郎醫生知道自己時間不多了
Dr. Ichiro protected me.
為了保護我
And bearing the disgrace of medical malpractice as his own,
一肩扛起醫療過失的恥辱
he left this world.
離開了這個世界
This is the truth.
這就是真相
For me,
對我來說
it was your father.
是你的父親
Dr. Ichiro Tokai is the one who spared my life.
是渡海一郎醫生，救了我的命
"It was all my responsibility."
“那都是我的責任”
If only you had said that,
如果你可以這麼說
my father wouldn't have died like that.
那我父親就不用背著那樣的名聲死去
Why did you stay quiet?
你為什麼不說？
If saying something would have saved Mr. Iinuma, I would have.
如果說出來能救患者的命 我早就說了
I would have happily been fired.
就算被開除我也毫無怨言
But without me, who could treat this patient?
但沒有我，誰能救這名患者呢？
If the forceps were to be removed, the patient would die.
拿出止血鉗，患者就會沒命
Dr. Tokai, not even you could save him.
渡海，甚至連你都救不了他
A doctor who overestimates his own skill
高估自已能力的醫生
could never save this patient.
不可能治好這個患者
That's why I couldn't tell anyone.
所以我才沒有告訴任何人
Hate me if you must.
你想恨我就恨吧
Kill me if you want to.
想殺就殺
But I will save this patient
無論如何我都會救這位病患
even if I die.
犧牲性命也在所不惜
These black forceps.
這把黑色止血鉗
That is what they're for.
就是為此而生的
They serve as a reminder to me as well.
這也是為了提醒我自己
No doctor, even myself,
我們當醫生的
is perfect.
不是完人
This cannot be forgotten.
千萬別忘了這點
Without arrogance,
切勿驕矜自喜
continuously hone your skills,
繼續磨練本領
keep questioning what medical care is really all about.
並時常反省醫療真正的意義
A testament to one's resolve.
這就是決心的證明
These black forceps…
使用黑色止血鉗的人…
only need to be used by me.
有我一個就足夠了
When the time comes to use them,
等到要使用那把黑色止血鉗時
that will be the time…
就是我
that I resign from being a surgeon.
要辭去外科醫生的時候
This…
我一直…
is what I've lived for.
為了這個信念才撐到現在
And now,
如今…
my work…
我的工作
is done.
已經完成了
Hand me the black forceps.
把黑色止血鉗給我
Right.
是
Goodbye,
再見
Dr. Ichiro Tokai.
渡海一郎
Suction.
抽吸
Right.
是
Blood pressure, 80. Stabilized.
血壓80，穩定了
It stopped…
終於止住了
We'll close him up.
把他縫合吧
Tokai.
渡海
Doctors are not perfect.
醫生並不完美
There is still much more
還有很多地方
for all of us to learn.
需要我們去學習
-Hurry, close him up. -But…
-快點縫合啊 -但是…
The black forceps are made of a special carbon.
黑色止血鉗是用特殊碳材製成的
They won't appear in X-rays.
X光拍不出來
They will turn to ash when he's cremated.
火葬時會一起化為灰燼
Close him up now.
縫合吧
Those are my orders.
這是教授的命令
Right.
是
-5-0, please. -Okay.
-5-0縫線 -好
Nurse, support me, please.
護理師，麻煩您協助我
Okay, understood.
是，知道了
The black forceps' duties have been fulfilled.
黑色止血鉗已經完成它的使命
And so have mine.
我也是
From now on…
從今以後…
-Dr. Saeki! -Professor Saeki!
-佐伯醫生！ -佐伯教授！
-Take him to Operating Room 2! -Dr. Saeki!
-把教授送到第二手術室 -佐伯醫生！
Professor!
教授！
One, two, three.
一、二、三
He's experiencing aortic dissection. Prepare to open him up.
主動脈剝離，準備開胸
-Right. -Where's Dr. Tokai?
-是 -渡海醫生人呢？
Dr. Tokai.
渡海醫生
Please leave your message after the tone.
請在嗶聲後留言
Dr. Tokai, where are you? The professor collapsed.
渡海醫生，您在哪裡？教授暈倒了
We need you, now!
請您馬上過來！
Also, when Dr. Saeki fell…
還有，教授暈倒的時候…
Well…
那個…
At Tojo's very own Saeki Surgery Department,
在我們東城大學醫院的佐伯外科
we perform an on-pump, on-beat…
進行了體外循環自主心跳的…
You already said that.
你已經說過了
Where is Professor Saeki?
佐伯教授在哪裡？
The truth is he had to return to the hospital for an emergency.
因為突發情況，他回醫院了
Please forgive us
給各位添麻煩了
for letting you all down.
非常抱歉
Is Dr. Saeki the only doctor at Tojo University?
東城大學只有佐伯醫生一個醫生嗎？
This is exactly the situation I feared most,
這就是我現在最擔心的事
having to rely solely on the skills of special individuals.
必須依賴某位醫生的個人技術
A man in such high demand as Dr. Saeki
像佐伯教授這麼忙碌的人
surely can't be entrusted with the position of board chairman.
當然不能被委以理事長的職務
The bleeding won't stop. Gauze!
出血不止，紗布！
-Right. -Blood pressure, 80.
-是 -血壓80
His heart rate is falling.
心肺功能開始下降
-Dr. Sera, where's Dr. Tokai? -I don't know.
-世良醫生，渡海醫生在哪裡？ -不知道
-Heart-lung machine, now! -Right.
-快點啟動人工心肺機 -是
SCHEDULED FOR RECONSTRUCTION
（預定施工地）
TOJO UNIVERSITY HOSPITAL FORMER WING
（東城大學醫院舊館）
It seems like Dr. Saeki will not be returning.
看樣子佐伯教授應該回不來了
Why don't we move on to the voting?
不如開始投票吧？
Right. Okay, then.
是啊，那麼
Excuse me.
不好意思
In place of Dr. Saeki,
請允許我代替佐伯醫生
I would like to use this time to speak.
跟大家說幾句話
Last night,
昨天晚上
I spoke with Dr. Saeki.
我跟佐伯醫生談過話
Are you sure you are fit for this?
您的身體真的可以嗎？
Please keep this a secret to the board members.
請您向各位理事保密
Do you want this that badly?
您就那麼想要嗎？
The seat of chairman.
這個理事長的位置
My life
我的命
is no longer only my own.
已經不止屬於我自己
I'm here today
是因為很多人的幫助
because many people protected me.
我今天才能坐在這裡
Above all,
最重要的是
I have to show something for it.
我必須有所表現
What I was entrusted with
把我的畢生所學
and what I learned through experience.
展現出來
Doctor…
醫生…
I believe…
我認為…
all doctors must always remain humble.
醫者必須時常保持謙遜
Be it surgical skill,
無論是外科醫生的技術
or advanced technology, there is always a limit.
還是最新的醫療技術，都有其限制
When faced with a human life,
當面對的是一條人命時
there is only so much we can do.
兩者都不是完全可靠
That's why…
正因為如此
we must use both.
才需要它們相輔相成
We must work together.
彼此截長補短
We must strengthen them both.
必須讓兩者變得更強
To save patients' lives in the future,
未來才能拯救更多的患者
we need the latest research.
我們需要最新的研究
To save the patients who are suffering in front of us
為了救治眼前受病痛折磨的病人
we need the best skills.
我們需要最高明的醫術
We cannot afford to lose either of them.
兩者缺一不可
These two opposing ideals
看似對立的兩個概念
must be allowed to coexist
要能和平共存
for the future of medicine.
這才是未來的醫療所需要的
That is Dr. Saeki's goal.
佐伯醫生一直懷抱這個目標
Blood pressure dropping!
血壓持續降低
Damn it. The tear is too large, we can't stop the bleeding.
可惡，撕裂口太大，來不及止血
Isn't there anything else we can do?
沒別的辦法了嗎？
His heart has stopped!
他的心跳停止了！
Dr. Saeki!
佐伯醫生！
-Give him a shot of adrenaline! -Right!
-注射一劑腎上腺素 -是
Start heart massage.
開始心臟按摩
For me, it was your father.
對我來說，是你父親
Dr. Ichiro Tokai is the one who spared my life.
是渡海一郎醫生，救了我的命
MISSED CALL FROM SERA
（世良的未接來電）
Dr. Tokai, where are you?
渡海醫生，你在哪裡？
The professor collapsed. We need you, now!
教授暈倒了，請您馬上過來
Also, when Dr. Saeki fell…
還有，佐伯教授暈倒時…
-Professor Saeki! -Dr. Saeki!
-佐伯教授！ -佐伯醫生！
Professor!
教授！
Tokai…
渡海…
Just be yourself.
你做自己就好
Just be normal.
當個普通的醫生
Doctors…
醫生…
Need only to think of their patients.
只要考慮患者
Save lives.
救人性命就好
Tokai…
渡海…
Just save people's lives.
你只要救人就好
To you…
我把一切
I entrust everything to you.
都交付給你了
"I entrust everything to you."
“我把一切都交付給你了”
That's what he said.
這是他說的
Whether accumulating research
無論是累積各項研究
or honing one's skills,
還是磨練技能
in the end, it's people.
到頭來，關鍵都是人
Striving for the incomplete to be made perfect,
正是因為有缺陷的人在追求完美
medicine continues to advance.
醫療才得以持續進步
That is Dr. Saeki's hope
這既是佐伯教授的想法
and his wish.
也是他的期望
We still haven't got a heartbeat!
還是沒有心跳
Don't give up.
不准放棄
If we give up, it's over.
要是放棄，一切就都完了
If we give up…
放棄的話
We won't be able to…
我們就沒辦法…
It's not over yet.
還沒有結束
It's not over yet!
還不到結束的時候！
It's…
一切…
It's not over, is it?
還沒有結束吧？
Dr. Tokai.
渡海醫生
Move it.
讓開
Okay!
是
Gown.
手術服
-Right. -Five minutes since the heart stopped.
-是 -心跳停五分鐘了
-Okay, we still have time. Continue. -Right.
-好，還有時間，繼續 -是
-Is the heart-lung machine ready? -Almost.
-人工心肺機準備好了嗎？ -差不多了
-Turn it on when it's ready. -Turning it on now.
-好了就立刻啟動 -啟動了
-Set it to cooling down. -Right.
-開始降溫 -是
Get all the gauze and artificial blood vessels you can.
人工血管和紗布，有多少備多少
-Change places. -Thank you.
-交換位置 -是
-Magnifying glass. -Here.
-放大鏡
-Metz.
-手術剪 -是
-Cut circulation. -Right.
-停止循環
-3-0. -Here.
-3-0號線 -是
-Suturing. -Right.
-開始縫合
Keep bringing more gauze.
再多拿點紗布來
-Dr. Sera, follow the thread. -Okay.
-世良，線跟上 -是
-Follow me. -Right.
-跟上
-Takashina, suction deeper.
-高階，再往裡面一些 -是
And now, the election results.
現在，公布投票結果
Professor Nishizaki, Teika University.
帝華大學，西崎教授
JAPAN SURGICAL SOCIETY BOARD CHAIRMAN ELECTION
（日本綜合外科學會 次年度理事長選舉）
Professor Saeki, Tojo University.
東城大學，佐伯教授
All right!
太好了！
Professor Nishizaki, Teika University.
帝華大學，西崎教授
-More suction. -Right.
-繼續抽吸 -是
Artificial vessels.
人工血管
-Open wider, I can't see. -Right.
-再展開一點，看不到 -是
-Sera, suction deeper.
-世良，再往裡面抽吸
-Gauze. -We need gauze.
-紗布 -拿紗布來
Professor Nishizaki, Teika Univerisity.
帝華大學，西崎教授
Professor Saeki, Tojo University.
東城大學，佐伯教授
Artificial vessel sutured. Removing clamp.
人工血管縫合完畢，解除阻斷
Okay.
是
-Get the DC just in case. -Okay.
-先準備直流去顫器 -是
There we go.
開始
-VF! -Dr. Tokai.
-心室纖維顫動 -渡海醫生
If his heart doesn't work, he won't make it.
無法恢復正常的話 佐伯教授就沒救了
-Defibrillator. -Here.
-去顫器 -是
Let him hear your voice.
他現在能聽到你們的聲音
-Talk to him. -Dr. Saeki.
-跟他說話 -佐伯醫生
Dr. Saeki!
佐伯醫生！
-Come back! -Here we go.
-快恢復啊 -開始
-Professor Saeki! -Doctor Saeki!
-佐伯教授！ -佐伯醫生！
-Doctor! -Nothing!
-醫生！ -沒反應
-Come back to us. -Professor!
-快恢復啊！ -教授
-Come back. -Professor Saeki.
-恢復吧！ -教授！
-Dr. Saeki! -Here we go.
-佐伯醫生！ -開始
-Nothing yet. -Please!
-還是沒反應 -求求您了！
-Stay alive! -Come back.
-撐下去啊！ -快恢復！
Come back to us.
活下來啊！
-Come back!
-挺住吧！ -撐下去！
He has a pulse. Blood pressure stabilizing!
有脈搏了，血壓恢復正常！
Dr. Tokai.
渡海醫生
Professor Saeki…
佐伯教授…
Professor Saeki, Tojo University.
東城大學，佐伯教授
And now, the final vote.
下面是最後一票
Let's go.
我們走
Professor Nishizaki.
西崎教授
Where are you going?
您要去哪裡？
To do some research.
去做研究
That's what makes a doctor.
這才是醫生
Why did you save me?
為什麼要救我？
Accepting you into Tojo University
把你招進東城大學
was my attempt at atoning for my sins.
就是為了減輕我的罪孽
But you…
但是你…
possessed an immeasurable talent for surgery.
卻擁有成為外科醫生不可限量的天分
With your grudge towards me,
因為怨恨我
you continued to hone your skills.
而不斷磨練自己的技術
I wanted to see…
我想要親眼看到
your growth…
你的成長
I wanted to observe more of it.
我想要看到更多
That's what I thought.
這是我的心願
I…
我…
wouldn't have cared if I died.
應該如你所願
As you wished.
死了就好了
Tokai.
渡海
"Just be yourself."
“你做自己就好
"Just be normal."
當個普通的醫生
"A doctor needs only to think of their patients."
醫生只要考慮患者
"Save lives."
救人性命就好
"Just save people's lives."
只要救人性命就好”
Those words
這些話
are from a doctor I respect.
是我尊敬的醫生所說的
Will you be leaving?
您要離開嗎？
At a university hospital like this,
大學附設醫院這種地方
someone has to take responsibility.
總要有人出來承擔責任的
What about me?
那我呢？
What will happen to me?
我怎麼辦？
I still have so much to learn.
我還有很多東西要學
I've worked so hard to keep up with you.
我一直努力想要追趕上您
I put myself through hell just to be useful to you!
吃了那麼多苦頭 只希望能幫上您的忙
How can you suddenly walk away like this?
您怎麼能這樣說走就走？
What about the hundred million yen?
那個一億圓呢？
I still owe you the money.
我還欠您錢
But…
但是
I haven't paid anything back.
我一毛錢都還沒還
So you can use me all you want.
所以您可以繼續任意使喚我
Order me around.
差遣我
Just please don't leave.
總之請您不要走
Fine.
知道了
I'm starving.
我餓死了
-What? -Make me some rice.
-什麼？ -幫我煮飯
-What? Rice? -Now.
-什麼？煮飯？ -快去
Right.
是
Bye.
再見
I hope you'll become a good doctor.
希望你成為一個好醫生
And so, Dr. Saeki was appointed chairman of the Japan Surgical Society.
就這樣，佐伯教授獲任命為 日本外科學會理事長
After carrying out the necessary organizational reforms,
在進行必要的組織改革之後
he promptly handed the position to a doctor from another university.
他果斷地把理事長之位 讓給其他大學的教授
He is now focusing on training and guiding young doctors for the future.
現在專心培育與指導未來的醫生
Try to feel it in the needle.
試著感受針頭的位置
Still seeking the position of chairman, Professor Nishizaki from Teika University
另外，帝華大學的西崎教授 仍然渴望理事長職位
put his efforts into a new research unit.
他致力於成立新的研究單位
I want Impact Factor!
我想要的是影響因子
Impact Factor!
影響因子！
Dr. Takashina, after learning from both doctors,
曾在他們兩位手下學習的高階醫生
acted as the brains of the surgery department, introducing new technology,
成為外科的智囊，引進最新醫療技術
and continued to pour his energy into his research.
並持續為研究傾注心血
But just like me,
不過，他和我一樣
from time to time,
三不五時
he showed a somewhat lonely expression.
會流露落寞的神情
Dr. Tokai did that?
是渡海醫生嗎？
He sent all the money he made to organizations that help patients
他好像把賺來的錢都捐給
who have suffered from medical malpractice.
協助醫療失誤受害者的組織
Come to think of it, I never did see him spend any money.
回想起來 的確沒看到渡海醫生花什麼花錢
Yes.
是啊
Do you want some, Dr. Sera?
世良醫生，要吃一點嗎？
I said wouldn't.
都說了不吃
I'm waiting to eat with Dr. Tokai.
我要等著和渡海醫生一起吃
And when will that be?
那要等到什麼時候？
-I have a bone to pick with him. -By the way,
-我還要跟他算帳 -說到這個
it seems there was an unidentified deposit the other day.
幾天好像有人匿名匯了一筆錢
The amount was ten million yen.
金額是一千萬
-Ten million? -That means…
-一千萬？ -也就是說…
No way.
不可能吧
Move it.
礙事
For ten million,
給我一千萬
I'll make the whole thing disappear.
我就幫你處理掉
Subtitle translation by: Tom Grathwol
字幕翻譯：莊雅婷